CHUKWUEBUKA AZUBUOGU NNABUGWU

36, Ajayi Street, Yaba, Lagos State | | +2348138609363 | |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nnabugwu-chukwuebuka-8b465412b||

Email: nnabugwukelvin.chukwuebuka@gmail.com

Career Summary

An enthusiastic data analyst with a proven ability to communicate with both technical professionals and end-users to identify critical analytic requirements and develop valuable solutions to drive process efficiency. Proven data integration experience in handling big data, providing data solutions that would lead to an increase in sales, total customer satisfaction, and as well as providing data insights on attracting new customers. Proven knowledge on the daily business across the FinTech space and competition across the market.

Experience

Data Analyst: eTranzact International Plc (2020-Present)

- Automated all real time fund transactions across eTranzact platform for proper insight analysis of hourly, daily, weekly and monthly transaction history.
- Developed and modified existing analytical dashboards for performance improvement and ease of business model interaction with clients.
- Developed and maintained the CEO and Executive dashboard for all the business model within the company.
- Mobile view dashboard creation using Microsoft Power BI and Report Builder for real time and handy monitoring of the companies transaction.
- Worked directly with the database connection and developed scripts to keep to real time transaction pull for analytical performance and transaction check across the FinTech Company.
- Microsoft Power BI development expert, interpreting trends and creating stories for the Executives in the company
- Data cleaning, modeling and extraction using SQL in pulling out data from the server.
- Business Analyst and storytelling expert with Microsoft Power BI, Excel, and SQL.

Data Analyst: Research Assistant (2019 -2020)

- Worked directly as a data analyst for an Associate Professor at Lagos Business School, in analyzing a big data set on South Africa demography and crime rate as well as providing visible visuals to tell the story behind the data.
- Performing Geocoding using Python scripts in extracting and collecting of real time geolocation of several research points and projects
- Developed a high storytelling and insights through analyzing the COVID-19 impact in Nigeria and the sentimental analysis of Nigerians towards the pandemic using Microsoft Power BI.

Project Analyst: Education Cooperation Society (2018-2019)

• Delegate responsibilities and analysed the daily work flow of different projects carried out across the states in Nigeria

• Evaluation of work flow, success and provided critical evaluations that led to the speed up of work channels.

Education

University of Nigeria, Nsukka

BSc Geology September 2012 _ July 2017

Certification

Microsoft Certified Data Analyst Associate

December 2021

Dataquest Lab, Inc

Python for Data Science

March 2020

Utiva Data Academy

Data Analytics: SQL and Power BI

November 2019

Microsoft Cooperation

Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Microsoft Power BI

November 2019

Awards and Achievements

- Award and commendation by the MD/CEO of Etranzact for the best performer in the company for the year 2021
- Efficient creation of standardized visuals for companies' data, for visualization insights.
- Provided a trend in information for company's decision making beforehand which led to avoidance of wrong decision making.
- Analyzed the dataset of coronavirus pandemic spread across the world and published it, to create insight on the affected regions.
- Published an article on the commonwealth Youth blog, and I was selected as the correspondent for the month of November based on the uniqueness and clarity of the report.
- Generated over 200,000 as the Vice President of National Association of Petroleum Explorationist University of Nigeria Chapter from the parent body in 2015.
- As the president of National Association of Petroleum explorationist, I organized a geological field work and conveyed about 50 students to the field for active geological exposure.
- Exciting World of Geology: I led an outreach to secondary school students where I spoke to about 400 students concerning the field of Geosciences.

Skills

Problem Resolution; Organized a fundraiser while serving as vice president and president of National Association of Petroleum Explorationist UNN chapter, which generated about 200,000 Naira.

Team Work; Acted as team lead in Utiva Data Hackathon Challenge of big data, which took us to the 3rd position of the competition.

IT Skills; Technology savvy, vast in using Microsoft office package (Word, PowerPoint, Excel formulas, VLOOKUP, Pivot tables etc.), Microsoft Power BI, SQL, DAX, M Language and python in big data analysis and visualization. Built reports and dashboards communicating monthly and yearly sales report.

Creativity and Innovation; Built models to visualize the Coronavirus pandemic spread across the nation and prepared reports on how best to mitigate the contamination.

Communication Skills; Completed a general studies course (English Language; Effective Written and Verbal Communication) in the University. An active Commonwealth Youth Nigerian Correspondent.

• Focused and Motivated • Cu

• Customer Oriented

Work Ethic

• Business Analysis

• Analytical Mind

• Can-do attitude

Attention to Details

• Numerical Skills

Time Management

Profile Details

Sex: Male

Hobbies: Football, Music